Damla Mazlum Celikbas

Cloud Engineer

Results-driven software developer and AWS Cloud Engineer, seeking to use proven Python, JSON, Linux and Core AWS Services knowledge to deliver coding excellence and cloud computing solutions. Before deciding a career change, worked as a Senior Poject Management Engineer with 9 years of experience managing variety of projects. Created effective communication between engineering team, suppliers, programme team and senior management. Strong background in problem solving, time management and with proven leadership skills.

Work History

2021-01

AWS

- present

- Completed 12 week, full-time, classroom based skills development and training program on IT fundamentals, AWS Cloud, and professional skills.
- Built IT fundamental skills, including: working knowledge of Linux OS, writing scripts in Python and Shell.
- Learned how to apply core AWS services in the area of compute, storage and networking, including EC2, S3, IAM, VPC, Lamda, Cloud Formation, RDS and Route 53.
- Demonstrated strong verbal and written communication skills, including the ability to explain technical information and terminology to non-technical end users e. Learned how to configure, monitor and support the suite of core AWS services.

2019-12 - 2020-09

Senior Project Engineer

AWS re/Start Trainee

Alten Ltd UK

- Consultant Engineer in Air Intake Systems (AIS) team in Jaguar Land
 Rover
- Lead project management of team of 8 component engineers.
- · Managed team goals and metrics.
- Represented the team working with multifunctional teams to ensure programme deliverables are met on time, scope and cost.
- Confirm and communicate programme assumptions and changes to the AIS team.
- Chair Engineering Issue Reviews (AIMS) on behalf of AIS Engineering team to resolve roadblocks.

2019-02

- 2019-04

Design and Release Engineer

RLE International UK

- Consultant Engineer in Body Closures team in Aston Martin Lagonda.
- Responsible for development and delivery of components (Decklid, Decklid Hinges and Gas Strut) on time to cost, weight and PSW targets.
- Support the management and coordination of engineering deliverables
- Resolved technical conflicts to programme requirements as per Gateway deliverables process in a timely manner.

2018-04

Cost Reduction Engineer

RLE International UK

• Consultant Engineer in Body Structures and Body in White Cost Reduction team in Aston Martin Lagonda.

Personal Info

Email

damlamzlm@gmail.com

Phone

+44 7985 492713

Address

134 Batsford Road CV6 1AU Coventry

Skills

**** Project management Time management *** Communication **** Problem solving *** Aws Core services *** Windows *** Linux *** Python programming language *** Sql **** HTML,CSS,JS **** C# Programming Language

Education

Benchmarking

- 2010-06

Ms office

Cost reduction

Supplier management

Yildiz Technical University, Istanbul

B. Eng., Mechanical Engineering

Courses

SQL

Codecadamy 2020

C#

By kodlama.io - practiced in Visual Studio 2019

- Lead multiple cost reduction projects from concept to product introduction.
- Developed detailed project plans to ensure cross-functional resource availability and allocation for approved cost-reduction projects.
- Kick off each project and review the timing with all stakeholders within in the company and suppliers.
- During project design development phase, created Engineering Design
 Decision Matrix in order to decide the best design and financial return for the business.
- Managed changes to the project scope, project schedule and project costs using appropriate verification techniques

2017-09 - 2018-04

Product Development Engineer

Jaguar Land Rover

- · Responsible for development of Brake Pads
- Managed engineering design and releasing using JLR systems (AIMS, PACN, WERS)
- Applied Failure Mode Avoidance techniques (FMEA)
- Managed Design Verification Plan for testing conducted at the supplier and at JLR
- Analysed test reports/data and recorded in RMDV.

2014-11 - 2017-09

Project Support Engineer

Jaguar Land Rover

- Worked as a Cross Car Line Support Engineer in Foundation Brakes
 Engineering team and worked ~10 vehicle programmes at a time
- Increased efficiency within the team by rolling out internal processes and documents.
- Created 'Part Number Complexity Matrix ' and rolled out updates to ensure part details for each programme and build is correct and up-to-date
- Created 'Requirement Management Complexity Matrix' to plan gateway timing of tests and part requirement for each test.
- · Lead Cost Reduction (TVM) Projects.

2014-03 - 2014-10

Business Planner

Jaguar Land Rover

- Lead VLBR (Vehicle Line Business Review) projects, managed work streams and delivery of opportunities
- Benchmark competitor vehicles and analyse to capture opportunities
- Worked with multi-functional teams to identify opportunities that generate VLBR actions (eg. feature/option offering, pricing, accessories, warranty issues, legal landscape,OXO charts)
- Assisted in the development of business cases to ensure activities have a
 positive impact on vehicle line profitability.
- Integrated VFM/TVM and other cost reduction opportunities into vehicle line activities and plans
- Prepared PDL (Product Direction Letter) documentation for handover to the relevant programme team for implementation.

2011-04 - 2013-06

Sales and Marketing Engineer

CVS Technologies

- Managed the development and production of proposal responses to requests for proposals/quotations (RFPs / RFQs)
- Analyzed RFP requirements and prepared proposal outlines.
- Travelled to visit potential and existing clients in Europe.
- · Provided technical and engineering information to clients
- · Liaised with key stakeholders to develop scope of work and strategy

Braking of Road Vehicles

TAS Module - University of Bradford - 2015

AutoCad

TMMOB (Chamber of Mechanical Engineers Turkey)

Certificates

Project Management

Yildiz Technical University & Istanbul Institute - 2011

Advanced Sales Techniques and Persuasion Methods

Istanbul 2012

5 Day Coding Challenge by Code Institute - August 2020

HTML,CSS,JS

Hobby

Learning new Programming Languages
Nature Photography
Hiking
Gardening